Hello everyone
Recently, Moltbot has been very popular
It was originally called Clawbot
Recently renamed, some people say this product is hype
but personally I think if you haven't used it
then you definitely shouldn't say that
I was the first to learn about it through Karpathy at the end of last year.
learned about this product from the comments in his post
in mid-January
I also cloned its repository locally
However, since I haven't actually experienced this product
I don't know how this product actually performs
Recently, I followed the official Moltbot website
deployed it according to the Railway tutorial
However, during usage, service interruptions frequently occur.
Troubleshooting is not as convenient as it is locally.
So recently I've deployed Clawbot
deployed on my other idle Mac
At the end of this video, I will also introduce how to use Mac's dual-machine collaboration
In today's video
I won't explain how to install it
Because there are already many excellent tutorials available in the market.
It can be installed on a VPS
including our domestic cloud service providers
actually provides detailed related tutorials
allows you to deploy to DingTalk
Red, etc.
I will introduce the tasks I've accomplished using Clawbot
Moltbot's very detailed gameplay
and brilliant community use cases
including reproducible prompt templates
and a guide on how to enable Clawbot for multitasking in parallel
Finally, we will also introduce the Telegram operation commands.
First, let's take a look at what Moltbot is
It is not purely a standalone chatbot
more like a system of agents with execution capabilities
You send a message to the Gateway
get away
The agent receives messages and runs once
agent loop
then route the result back to the original chat window
These key terms, everyone can take a look to understand
We will frequently use the file locations
For example, the global configuration
It is located in the moltbot.json file.
After connecting to Telegram
The first thing to do is to pair by entering /start
First, type /start
then you will receive a reply from the bot like this
At the bottom, we can see this line of command
Because here I also have the command from before it was renamed
If you are now using the new version
then pay attention to how Telegram replies to you
Just use the new command
Moltbot by default folds all DMs
placed in a main session, and the /commands
It can skyrocket our efficiency
I will also provide a detailed introduction later.
One of the great things about Moltbot is its Skills.
There's a lot of content here. You just need to send it a GitHub link
You just need to send it a GitHub link
then let it install
It will be installed quickly
ClawdHub is created by the author of Clawd
a skill repository website built by
We come to the official Moltbot website
Finally, there is a ClawdHub
There are a lot of Skills here
We can enter such a username
This is Clawd, the author himself
He has built a great number of Skills.
super awesome
By the way,
Such an awesome Moltbot skills, it aggregates
There are numerous amazing Skills in ClawdHub, and you can browse through this repository to pick the Skill you want to use.
Moltbot's default Memory has two layers
First is the daily journal, which is organized in a date-based format.
The second one is long-term memory.
after prolonged use
your conversations will undergo Compaction or Pruning
Its search tool defaults to using Brave
is very good
It also provides for free users
2,000 calls per month are completely sufficient
Its query results are cached for 15 minutes by default.
Moreover, it also features a wide range of Browser tool plugins.
It also has an Exec tool
allows the Bot to execute commands within the workspace
This is why people say Clawbot
you should isolate it
Do not let it run on your main computer
The main point is that there is significant risk in this area.
If you don't want to rely entirely on CLI
Control UI is very useful
By default, it's this address
It will display in detail every conversation you have with the bot.
You can see the detailed tool invocation flow
Let's take a look at some of the popular trends on social media.
It can proactively send you morning briefings and handle email follow-ups.
schedule arrangement
the production pipeline for project research content
Of course, it can also help you with Vibe Coding
as long as it is given a good skill
its capabilities are expanded
From this perspective
The more popular Moltbot becomes
the entire ecosystem will become more prosperous
Let's take a quick look
For different use cases,
how to give it prompts
I'll put this part of the content on the Planet.
If you're interested, you can take a look
For example, the company here is researching content production pipelines
how to develop prompts
and skill self-evolution
Now let's take a detailed look at what Clawbot
What tasks has it helped me complete
After I paired with it,
First, I had it help me search for the trending news from the past 24 hours.
It prompted me to first obtain the Brave API key
After setting it up
it can immediately provide me with the search results
After that, I asked it to install a new Skill
This Skill can download videos
It was quickly installed
It told me I had to restart Clawdbot
After I restarted it
let it summarize this video
Soon it downloaded the subtitles and summarized them.
Here, I'm using MiniMax M2.1, which is very fast.
Its programming capabilities are quite impressive.
particularly suitable for writing small scripts
So it's very suitable to use in Clawbot
After that, I prompted it
I said only the text is needed, no subtitle formatting
It will convert it into plain text for me within seconds.
and save it locally
After that,
have it write a high-quality article
and ask it to search for more information
Here I prompt it to remember
Whenever I mention the download directory in the future
then help me put it in such a local directory on my computer
We can see that it replied saying it has remembered my preference.
It quickly found the search results
But I took a look
These two images are not related to Ollama.
So I asked it to modify it again
and it provided an image in which
Initially it used the PNG format
Later, it helped me change it to SVG format before it worked.
I checked the SVG it provided
the Ollama SVG
which means it helped me find
and downloaded it to my local device
When we chat with it on Telegram
It supports sending multiple messages to it
It can invoke sub-agents
can help you complete tasks in parallel
For example, here, I ask it to search for usage examples of Clawbot users
excellent cases
at least 5 articles into the download directory and
and search for 10 high-quality YouTube videos, download the subtitles
also needs to be placed in the same folder
it then starts the sub-agent
Moreover, each step is briefly explained.
After that,
we can see this
I see that the searched information has not been displayed yet
I sent it a new message again
Search for information on Kimi 2.5
and also summarize it
After that, you'll see it
Here it shows what the sub-agent is doing
In other words, we can send it multiple tasks simultaneously.
Here I need to add a point
I don't usually let AI download multiple YouTube videos for me.
Moreover, the topic of this video is very similar to the topic of the video I want to create.
Ah
This is something I wouldn't do
Here, it's just to test it.
The quality of its completion is very good
Then I had it convert the subtitle file into plain text
Ask it to summarize again
and also had it generate Mermaid diagrams with rich styling
It did a very good job
only one Mermaid diagram
rendering issue
Later, I converted the corresponding Mermaid diagram into ASCII.
Here it mentions sub-agents
Let's take a look at the Moltbot Multi-task Parallelism Guide
I was in the cloned official Moltbot repository
asked the AI
is asking how many main agents it supports concurrent execution
Then how many main agents does it support for concurrent execution?
and sub-agent parallelism, etc.
Then, the AI searched for information and told me that the Telegram bot
It has a message debounce
and it also has concurrent queue processing
The default is 4 concurrent tasks.
Tasks are automatically queued and prioritized.
efficient execution
Moltbot has a sessions_spawn tool
We then send complex tasks
the main agent analyzes it
and then calls the sub-agent
finally report the results
This advantage lies in long-running tasks
slow tools do not block the main process
Usage scenario comparison table, and the sessions will also be isolated
The cost will also be more optimized
Even if you don't use Moltbot
I think it's also necessary to study
how its code is written
The author of Moltbot, Peter,
In 2021, his product generated $110 million in sales.
He had already retired.
he made a comeback last year
The amount of code written every week is terrifying.
If we send multiple messages in the same Telegram chat
quickly send multiple Messages
it will merge the messages
If you wait for a reply before sending a new task, it will be processed in a queue.
Now let's take a look at
How to get Moltbot to help me create a Skill
Link to Replicate to call image or voice generation models
It first needs to understand some details
This counter-question is excellent.
I told it
it quickly prompted me, saying that this Skill has been created and is ready for testing
and it's ready for testing
I then sent the Replicate key to it
After that, it started prompting me that as long as I provided the prompt
it can generate images
It will run a test in the background on its own.
After that, I sent it a new link
about the seedream model
have it add this new model
After that, the test results came out quite well.
I also asked it to search for the weather in Shanghai for the next 15 days
and have it create a line chart
I think the quality is still very good
And the speed is also very fast
In addition to what was just mentioned
how it guided me to configure the Brave API key
help me install
video download Skill
It can also be set up to handle some other tasks, such as creating a local project
Create a cBode project
for storing coding projects
including having it configure Deepgram
for speech-to-text
Now let's take a look at
How to get Moltbot to help me with coding
First, I want it to help me come up with a file name
Then, I will prompt it to create a new subfolder in cbode
help me create one using remotion
Introduction video about Clawbot
I will definitely have it help me start it up
and have it add some content
Later, we will see such a video structure
and it will also have some simple UGC Anime effects
Finally, I also had it export the video
send it to the current bot window
This is the effect of the video it generated
This was all done entirely by itself.
I didn't write a single line of code.
After that, I had it search for a piece of background music
add voiceover to this remotion project
This is the final effect with the added Music it showcased
I think it's quite good
We can do it completely in any outdoor scenario
With a mobile phone, you can prompt Moltbot to help us do it
produce videos
It produces good results
we can have it rendered
send it to the current chat window
Let you see which areas can be adjusted
This is the new encoding mode.
This is why many people like Moltbot
It offers an exceptionally high degree of freedom.
compatible with multiple mobile applications
In addition to using this method to have Moltbot write code for me
You can also utilize a coding agent Skill
call Codex, or Claude Code
or other coding tools to help you write code
You can unleash your creativity anytime, anywhere.
Let's take a look at how to set up Deepgram.
I just directly send the key to it
let it set it up for me
as long as I send it voice files
or it obtains the audio from another source
can help me convert it into text
Soon, it told me that the Settings were configured to support various formats
After that, I sent a Chinese language snippet to it
It quickly converted it for me
After that, I sent it another English audio clip.
It told me that the quality of this speech transcription was poor
It might be an issue with the audio itself.
In fact, the audio quality is actually very good
That's because when it was initially set up,
did not add automatic audio language recognition
So I had it make the changes
it can then be used normally
We can see that adding a third-party API
is so incredibly simple
Now let's take a look at
Moltbot's operation commands in Telegram
The basic commands include /help, /commands, and /status.
Status allows you to check which model is currently being used.
context
how much of the length has been occupied
Use /think to set the thinking depth
/verbose can control the output of Tools and called information
/reasoning can control the visibility of the reasoning process
visibility, /model can switch models
/models lists the available models
/new starts a new conversation
We can use /skill
then specify the name to make it run the designated skill
/debug enter debug settings
/queue here to adjust queue settings
/subagents can manage sub-agents, and /queue's queue settings
Settings require some considerations.
By default, it's a new message that will guide the ongoing reply.
interrupt means new Messages will interrupt the current reply
followup is
New messages wait in queue, etc.
So if we use it at night
you can let it perform follow-up
We can also use inline commands
This way, sending it becomes a bit simpler.
Finally, let's talk about how to enable dual-machine collaboration on Mac
enable screen sharing and file transfer
allows you to easily operate on Mac A
and record the screen of Mac B
First, we can proceed on the controlled Mac computer
enable screen sharing in Settings
You can also enable file sharing
Remember the computer's name
Next, we can open Finder on Mac A's computer
left sidebar
locate the network location
Double-click on Mac B to connect, and then you can quickly access Mac B's hard drive.
Ah, the hard drive of B can be quickly opened.
screen sharing and file transfer
allows you to control two hosts from a single computer
It will be more convenient when you debug Moltbot.
That's all for today's introduction about Moltbot.
A great tool
For You to try it on an independent device
or try it on a VPS